Christopher Blaylock - Full Stack

Profile

I'm a former U.S. Navy Nuclear Engineer and Boeing Quality Engineer who discovered my passion for web development through The Odin Project and online tutorials. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React.js, I bring a conscientious approach to my work. I'm now building full-stack applications by expanding my backend expertise with Node.js, Express, and PostgreSQL.

Work Experience

Ħ 06/2022 - PRESENT ♥ CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA

Quality Engineer Boeing

- Streamlined critical production processes and led quality-focused initiatives on the 787 program.
- Reduced production flow by 33% through improved quality and defect reductions.

☐ 06/2017 - 06/2022

○ CHARLESTON, SOUTH CAROLINA

Nuclear Engineer US Navy

- Mentored over 1,000 nuclear submarine operators, emphasizing collaborative problemsolving while building confident, capable professionals.
- Led **teams of up to 30** in daily reactor operations, applying strong leadership and communication skills to maintain operational excellence.

Education

円 02/2024 - PRESENT

Software Development The Odin Project

Comprehensive web development curriculum.

⊟ 01/2021 − 05/2022

MBA

University of Florida

⊟ 08/2019 - 05/2021

Engineering Management University of Florida

⊟ 08/2013 − 05/2017

Nuclear Engineering University of Florida

Projects

File Uploader

https://github.com/cblaylock18/file-uploader Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL, Prisma, EJS, Cloudinary, Multer, Authentication, Sessions

• A full-stack file management system allowing file uploading, sharing, and organization.

Portfolio Site

https://github.com/cblaylock18/portfolio-site-v1
React, React Router, CSS Modules, Vite, Context
API, SPA

• A single-page app with dark mode toggle and a strong focus on a11y and responsive design.

Members Only

https://github.com/cblaylock18/members-only Node, Express, PostgreSQL, EJS, Passport.js, bcrypt, sessions

• A secure members-only message board with signup, log-in, authentication, sessions, and roles.

Shopping Cart App

https://github.com/cblaylock18/mock-shopping-cart
React, JavaScript, CSS Modules, React Router,
Vite, Vitest, FakeStore API

• A fully responsive eCommerce-style web app with real-time cart updates and product filtering.

Inventory Management App

https://github.com/cblaylock18/inventory-application

Node, Express, PostgreSQL, EJS, express-validator, CRUD

 A robust inventory management app, implementing full CRUD for categories, animals, and foster families with dynamic filtering.

Skills

(i) Frontend

React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Accessibility (a11y), Jest, Vitest, React Testing Library

(i) Backend

Node.js, Express, EJS, PostgreSQL, Prisma ORM, Auth (Passport.js, bcrypt.js), MVC Architecture

(i) Build & Deployment

Git, GitHub, Vercel, Railway, Webpack

(i) Collaboration

Scrum (CSM), Kanban